Kontakt

www.linkedin.com/in/ magdalenarogl (LinkedIn) www.microsoft.de (Company)

Top-Kenntnisse

Leadership Public Relations Diversity

Languages

Englisch (Professional Working)

Deutsch (Native or Bilingual)

Französisch (Elementary)

Certifications

Accessibility in Action

Community & Social Media Manager (Deutsche Presseakademie)

Honors-Awards

Digital Female Leader Award

"25 Frauen die unsere Wirtschaft revolutionieren"

Pathfinder Award

Top 50 Diversity Driver 2021

Magdalena Rogl

Project Lead Diversity & Inclusion, Microsoft Germany Bayern

Zusammenfassung

As part of Generation Y, I'm involved in the online world for over 15 years.

In 2016, I moved from the media industry to corporate communications at Microsoft Germany. My sustained commitment to equal opportunities and diversity - outside and inside our company - led to my current position as Project Lead for Diversity & Inclusion. For my unconventional career path as a kindergarden teacher into the digital industry, I was awarded with the Digital Female Leader Award and named one of the "25 Women Revolutionizing Our Economy".

I'm a value ambassador for the non-profit education initiative GermanDream and a role model for BayFid, the fellowship program of the Bavarian State Ministry for Digital Affairs.

Berufserfahrung

Microsoft

6 Jahre 2 Monate

Project Lead Diversity & Inclusion, Microsoft Germany Oktober 2021 - Present (7 Monate)

Munich, Bavaria, Germany

Board Member GLEAM & Friends (LGBTQI+ Employee Resource Group)

Juli 2017 - Present (4 Jahre 10 Monate)

Head of Digital Channels

März 2016 - Oktober 2021 (5 Jahre 8 Monate)

Deutschland

- · Managing Editor of the Corporate Communications Team
- · Leadership and Development of the Digital Channels Team
- Project Lead Social Media Communication, Newsroom, Blog, Video, Influencer Relations
- Media and Influencer Relationship Management

- Strategic Planning for the Digital Communication Channels
- Development of the Monitoring and Reporting Concept
- · Conceptual Modification of the Internal Corporate Influencer Program

Events, Podiumsdiskussionen, Konferenzen Speakerin, Moderatorin Dezember 2014 - Present (7 Jahre 5 Monate)

- Forbes
- ZEIT Wirtschaftsgipfel
- Handelsblatt
- Medientage München
- Bits & Pretzels
- dmexco
- CeBit
- Female Future Force Day
- Ada Lovelace
- KiKa Webtalk
- Female Future Force Day
- Kommunikationskongress
- Siemens
- DJV Kongress
- uvm

Tomorrow Focus AG

Managerin Online & Social Media Communications März 2013 - Januar 2016 (2 Jahre 11 Monate)

München und Umgebung, Deutschland

- Strategic development of corporate website and social media channels
- Project management Social Intranet (conceptual, technical and contentrelated)
- Newsletterser tests, UX, frontend, backend)
- Regular analysis of KPIs (reporting, monitoring)
- Influencers and Blogger Relations
- Employer branding (events, sweepstakes)
- Cooperation with universities in the field of online communication / social media (University of Mainz, University of Munich)

FOCUS Online

6 Jahre 6 Monate

Leitung Community Management

September 2011 - Februar 2013 (1 Jahr 6 Monate)

- Management of the user community at www.focus.de
- · Leadership of the community team
- Establishment and further development of the community (new functionalities, UX design)
- Conception and implementation of CRM measures
- Editorial integration of the community
- Writing community articles (user generated content)

Community Administration September 2006 - September 2011 (5 Jahre 1 Monat)

Ausbildung

Deutsche Presseakademie

Manager Social Media & Community Management, Social Media & Community Management · (2011 - 2011)

Fachakademie für Sozialpädagogik

Social Sciences · (2002 - 2004)